<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="cms">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2014 Niels Ole Salscheider

    Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this
    software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted
    without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in
    all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission
    notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of
    the copyright holders not be used in advertising or publicity
    pertaining to distribution of the software without specific,
    written prior permission.  The copyright holders make no
    representations about the suitability of this software for any
    purpose.  It is provided "as is" without express or implied
    warranty.

    THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS
    SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
    FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY
    SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
    WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN
    AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION,
    ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF
    THIS SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="wl_cms" version="1">
    <description summary="allows attaching a color space to a wl_surface">
      This interface allows attaching a color space to a wl_surface. This is
      used by the compositor to display the colors correctly. For this, the
      compositor converts any attached surfaces to the blending color space
      before the blending operations. After blending, the output surface is
      converted to the color space of the output device.
      This interface also provides requests for the sRGB and the blending color
      space. It further allows creation of a color space from an ICC profile.
      The client is informed by an event if the color space of one of the
      outputs changes.
    </description>

    <request name="set_colorspace">
      <description summary="set the color space of a wl_surface">
        With this request, the color space of a wl_surface can be set.
        The sRGB colorspace is attached to a surface before set_colorspace is
        called for the first time.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface" />
      <arg name="colorspace" type="object" interface="wl_cms_colorspace" />
    </request>

    <request name="colorspace_from_fd">
      <description summary="creates a color space from an ICC profile">
        This request allows creation of a wl_cms_colorspace object from an ICC
        profile. The fd argument is the file descriptor to the ICC profile (ICC
        V2 or V4).
      </description>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd" />
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_cms_colorspace" />
    </request>

    <request name="output_colorspace">
      <description summary="returns the color space for the requested output">
        This request returns a wl_cms_colorspace object for the requested
        output. A client can use this when it does not want its surfaces to be
        color-corrected. In this case it can attach the color space of its main
        output to its surfaces.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" />
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_cms_colorspace" />
    </request>

    <request name="srgb_colorspace">
      <description summary="tell the client what blending space is used">
        This request returns a wl_cms_colorspace object for the sRGB color
        space. The sRGB color space is initially attached to all surfaces.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_cms_colorspace" />
    </request>

    <request name="blending_colorspace">
      <description summary="tell the client what blending space is used">
        This request returns a wl_cms_colorspace object for the blending color
        space of the compositor. All surfaces are converted by the compositor
        to the blending color space before the blending operations. Once the
        blending is performed, a further color conversion to the output color
        spaces is carried out by the compositor.
        A client should render in the blending color space returned by this
        request if it does any color conversion on its own. This allows the
        compositor to skip the color conversion to the blending color space.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_cms_colorspace" />
    </request>

    <event name="output_colorspace_changed">
      <description summary="tell the client what color space an output has">
        This event will be sent when the color space of an output is changed.
      </description>
      <arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" />
    </event>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="invalid_profile" value="0"
             summary="the passed icc data is invalid" />
    </enum>
  </interface>

  <interface name="wl_cms_colorspace" version="1">
    <description summary="represents a color space">
      This interface represents a color space that can be attached to surfaces.
      It is used by the wl_cms interface.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroys the wl_cms_colorspace object">
        Informs the server that the client will not be using this protocol
        object anymore.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_profile_fd">
      <description summary="get a file descriptor to the profile data">
        This request will cause a profile_fd event that returns a file
        descriptor to the ICC profile data of this colorspace.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="profile_data">
      <description summary="file descriptor to the profile data">
        This event occurs after a get_profile_fd request and returns the file
        descriptor to the ICC profile data of this colorspace.
      </description>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd" />
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
